<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Gray Matter</title>
        <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Gray Matter</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>Mgeraldoj07@gmail.com (Gerald Maduabuchi)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>Mgeraldoj07@gmail.com (Gerald Maduabuchi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 18:19:39 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://graysnotes.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>How to Dockerize Spring Boot and PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/dockerizing-spring-boot-postgres/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 18:19:39 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/dockerizing-spring-boot-postgres/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction. In this article, I will walk you through the entire process of dockerizing a Spring Boot application, and connecting it to a PostgreSQL database which would be spun up in a seperate container. I assume you have a little knowledge of Docker. I initially planned to do a Docker tutorial. I think at the time of writing this&ndash;I have a draft on medium about it. Expect an article soon based on Docker.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Crash Course: Matplotlib and Jupyter Notebook</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/crash-course-matplotlib/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 23:37:44 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/crash-course-matplotlib/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction to Matplotlib. Matplotlib is a library used to create visualisations of data in the Python programming language. With matplotlib, you can create two-dimensional graphs using Python Scripts. It’s pretty cool and I will be showing you how you could use it for your subsequent projects, research and schoolwork alongside the Jupyter Notebook tool.
Jupyter Notebooks. A Jupyter Notebook is a locally hosted web application used for machine learning and data science tasks, which involves writing models, documenting models and visualising their implementation with tools such as Matplotlib or Seaborn (an alternative).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Writing better Git Commits</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/commiting-in-git/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 16:05:12 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/commiting-in-git/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction. In this article you would learn how to properly structure and craft decent, intuitive and readable commit messages that summarise the context of the code you published to either a remote or local branch of a repository. This would be helpful if you work on collaborative projects, and would also save you the mental stress of trying to figure out a commit. I was once guilty of creating incredibly confusing and inappropriate commit messages, that did not capture the context of my code.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Microservices, RPCs, SOAP, REST &amp; GraphQL</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/musketeers-of-api/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 11:27:55 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/musketeers-of-api/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction This article will cover the topic of application programming interfaces, which is an essential unit that makes up the microservice architecture.
The Microservice Architecture. The micro service architecture is a type of application architecture where the application is broken into several units, communicating effectively with each other over a network protocol. In contrast to monolith applications, which contains the entire logic, client side and server side units in one package that is deployed on a server.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Set up Tailwind and Storybook with Next</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/install-tailwind-storybook/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:56:38 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/install-tailwind-storybook/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction. In this article, you will learn how to install storybook and configure it with tailwindcss, in a Next JS project. I have used these tools to build several side projects of mine and even professional projects. I hope you find it interesting.
Why Tailwind and Storybook? It boils down to your preference. Storybook is a pretty nice tool that could be used alongside several CSS in options. From utility first frameworks such as tailwindcss, to Chakra UI, CSS in JS (Styled Components) or plain styling in CSS.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Avoiding The Oops in Oop</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/oops-in-oop/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:13:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/oops-in-oop/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction There is an awful lot that goes into writing good code that abides by proper Object-Oriented Programming principles. In this tutorial I will basically cover the importance and significance of writing quality code (though I feel that quality code is subjective) thereby avoding &ldquo;Oops in Oop.&rdquo;
Note: &ldquo;Oops&rdquo; is basically an exclamation made after a significant mistake or accident rather.
Getting Started Before being able to follow this tutorial and get the best out of it, you have to meet up with the following perquisites.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Set Up React With Laravel</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/set-up-react-with-laravel/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 09:09:15 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/set-up-react-with-laravel/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[How to set up Laravel with React JS. Introduction. Just like I was roaming Stackoverflow, you’ve probably been wondering how to set up React JS with the Laravel framework. React is arguably one of the most powerful libraries for building user-interfaces. Yes, it’s a library, not really a framework. It forms the view component of web applications. Laravel on the other hand, is a powerful open-source PHP framework used for building small to robust web applications.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Fibonacci Algorithms in C</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/fibonacci-in-c/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 16:59:56 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/fibonacci-in-c/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction This article covers the concept of Fibonacci series. A very popular algorithm in Computer Science. We would be implementing the theory practically in the C programming language.
What is the Fibonacci Series? The Fibonacci series is a unique set of series whereby the following term is always equal to the sum of the previous two terms. We could reframe this explanation in another perspective. We could refer to these series as a growing array or set of numbers where the previous sum of two terms is the determinant of the next term.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building An Image Classifier</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/building-image-classifier/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 14:05:25 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/building-image-classifier/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction. In this article, I will guide you through the processes I went through to create an image classifier using the Flask framework, the Keras library and Google&rsquo;s popular machine learning library, Tensorflow. It was quite an interesting project that managed to gain over nineteen stars on Github, as at the time of writing this article. I was really pleased with the project, thus I humbly decided to share the entire workflow.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence: The trend, myths, approaches, philosophy and science.</title>
    <link>http://graysnotes.com/posts/introduction-to-ai-2019/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 21:40:50 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Gerald Maduabuchi</author>
    <guid>http://graysnotes.com/posts/introduction-to-ai-2019/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Disclaimer Note: This article is basically an archive. In no way, shall it be modified to preserve its authenticity. The content of this article depending on the reader, may come off as sparse, evasive of detailed theoretical proof, philosphical, or driven by science fiction. The sole purpose of this article is to capture the minds of neutral persons, entertain or educate. This article, is merely an introspective view into the accumulated beliefs and understanding of quite an explorative teenager (fourteen at the time), trying to grasp the field of artificial intelligence.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
